A Guide to the Cartoons by Art Wood, 1952-1959, n.d.
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Cartoons by Art Wood, 1952-1959, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5235,-a
This collection is comprised of 635 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Patrons are to use microfilm. The collection is available for research use, and the microfilm may be borrowed through the inter-library loan system.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library by Art Wood in two groups; 475 cartoons were presented on December 7, 1955, and 160 were donated on April 4, 1966.
Alternative Form
This collection is also available on microfilm, Manuscripts Division reel #M2372.
Biographical/Historical Information
James Arthur (Art) Wood, Jr. (1927- ) was born in Miami, Florida, but grew up in the Washington, D.C. area. The political and social climate of the nation's capital fostered an early interest both in drawing and collecting political cartoons.
During World War II, Mr. Wood worked on the staff of the Navy magazine, All Hands, providing a Sunday comic characters, "All Thumbs," as well as served as an illustrator for military posters and brochures. After the war, he attended Washington and Lee University where he served on the editorial board of The Southern Collegian. Mr. Wood contributed cartoons to The Washington Star before becoming the first editorial cartoonist of The Richmond News Leader(1950-1956), and then The Pittsburgh Press(1956-1963). Mr. Wood then returned to live in Maryland, where he presently has a cartoon-and-illustration consulting service, Stam-Wood Productions.
Besides the newspapers mentioned above, Mr. Wood's cartoons have appeared in Time, Newsweek, U.S. News and World Report, Harper's, and other newspapers, including The New York Times. He is a founder and past president of the Association of American Editorial Cartoonists, and is a member of the National Cartoonists Society, Sigma Delta Chi, and the National Press Club. His work has been recognized by numerous national awards and exhibitions. His book, Great Cartoonists and Their Art,, was published in 1987 by Pelican Publishing Company. A noted cartoonist in his own right, Mr. Wood has actively collected original cartoons by others since he was twelve; his collection contains the better work of over 2000 artists and includes over 30,000 original drawings.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains 635 original cartoons drawn by Art Wood during the "Eisenhower Years," 1952-1959, and first published in two newspapers: The Richmond News Leader(Richmond, Virginia: 1952-1956) and The Pittsburgh Press(Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania: 1956-1959).
Besides their intrinsic artistic value, editorial cartoons provide significant political and social commentaries on the events and personalities which are their subjects, for not only do they form a chronicle of "the news," they interpret the news. The artist imbues his work with messages that reflect a given opinion or point of view, ranging from scenes conveying a sense of dignified solemnity to caricatures portraying great leaders as buffoons, with captions and labels intended to cause the reader to gain an insight that will result in a reaction, either positive or negative. Whether considered in a contemporary setting when initially published, or as historical commentary when later used to illustrate books and articles, to quote Mr. Wood, editorial cartooning is "one of the most influential mediums in the country. It's visual like television and has an immediate impact and a tremendous readership."
Among the 497 political cartoons collected by former Virginia Senator Harry F. Byrd, Sr. and presented to the University of Virginia Library with his papers (accession 9700) on March 2, 1971, are sixteen drawn by Art Wood. These cartoon may be viewed on microfilm M-2111.
Arrangement
The cartoons are arranged in chronological order, with the exception of those cartoons for which dates have not been established. Undated cartoons are in the order in which they were received. In the content listing, the caption is in upper case letters followed by significant labels or key words used in the cartoon.
Contents List
- BALANCING ACT 1952 JAN 06
  Political Parties Republican (GOP) Congress Federal Budget
- HALPP! 1952 APR 18
  Price controls & Wage controls National Economy
- ANOTHER BIG BOOM 1952 APR 24
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. Victory in PA, NY Pennsylvania New York
- COMING INTO COURT WITH UNCLEAN HANDS 1952 MAY 16
  Labor unions Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) threat
- AROUND THE FLAME 1952 MAY 20
  Germany Unification Russian proposals
- STILL HOWLING 1952 MAY 21
  Communists (Reds)s Korea n Truce Talks
- SURPRISE! 1952 JUL 02
  MacArthur, Douglas Mac in '52 ...it would be a tragic development...
- LETS SEE-14 OF THOSE, AND 17 OF THESE, AND... 1952 JUL 04
  GA, FL Georgia Florida Taft, Robert
- WHAT IT TAKES 1952 JUL 29
  A Political Parties Republican (GOP) adminis. Eisenhower, Dwight D. Abuses of power Political Parties Democrats (Dems) s
- OLD BALDY 1952 AUG 04
  Korea
- STORMY WEATHER 1952 AUG 06
  Coal Strikes Threat Steel strike Tornado Damage $
- THAT'S OUR BOY 1952 AUG 07
  Stevenson, Adlai E. Brannan Wyatt Americans for Democratic Action (ADA) Truman, Harry S. HST Fair Dealers
- THIS'LL BE TOUGHER THAN NORMANDY! 1952 AUG 19
  Invasion of the South Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- YOW!! 1952 AUG 22
  Fed Taxes State Tax City Tax Luxury Tax Hidden...
- THE THINKER 1952 AUG 25
  My Grandfather voted that way - my father voted... Voting
- ANOTHER RECORD FLIGHT 1952 AUG 28
  Cost of Living Round Trip Ireland to...
- NO RECESS FOR DEATH 1952 SEP 01
  Peace talks in recess Korea
- AND HE'S OFF! 1952 SEP 02
  Labor Day Full Scale Political parties Campaign
- REBEL YELL 1952 SEP 04
  Clean...mess in Washington, D.C. Eisenhower, Dwight D.'s Southern speech
- YOU SAID IT! 1952 SEP 08
  The important thing is not where we are but Stevenson, Adlai E.
- BUT LOOK BEHIND THE CURTAIN! 1952 SEP 15
  stories Corruption in Govt. Stevenson, Adlai E.
- FALL'S MOST IMPORTANT COLOR 1952 SEP 16
  Schools bus yellow
- DOCTOR OF LETTERS 1952 SEP 24
  to Stevenson, Adlai E. Stevenson Labor unions American Federation of Labor (AFL) Labor unions Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) National Association (NAACP) Americans for Democratic Action (ADA)
- SMOKESCREEN 1952 SEP 30
  Whistle stop #648 Truman, Harry S. view of "the facts"
- EISENHOWER HAS JOINED IN SPREADING A REPUBLICAN "WAVE OF FILTH"! 1952 OCT 07
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. Political parties Republicans (GOP)
- SOUTHERN DISCOMFORT 1952 OCT 15
  South I don't agree with Stevenson, Adlai E. but he's a Political Parties Democrats (Dems)ocrat
- VIRGINIA WATCHERS 1952 OCT 16
  Byrd, Harry F., Sr. Welcome Eisenhower, Dwight D.'s HQ Stevenson, Adlai E.'s HQ
- JAMBALA 1952 OCT 17
  Stevenson, Adlai E. public power private enterprise Truman, Harry S.HST Labor unions American Federation of Labor (AFL) Labor unions Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO)
- THE PIT AND THE PENDULUM 1952 OCT 18
  Byrd, Harry F., Sr. speech Stevenson, Adlai E.
- THE BOTTOM OF THE BARREL 1952 OCT 22
  The President of the US Filthy politics
- TOAST OF THE TOWN alternate: WHOEVER IT MAY BE 1952 NOV 05
  To the 34th President of the United States
- FAMOUS LAST WORDS 1952 NOV 06
  The bigger the voting e, the better for Political Parties Democrats (Dems)ocrats
- THE MIDDLE MAN 1952 NOV 20
  United Nations Russian obstruction
- THE NEW IMPROVED MODEL 1952 NOV 28
  Political parties Democrats (Dems) Cabinet Political Parties Republican (GOP) Cabinet Dulles, John F....McKay
- COLD STEEL 1952 DEC 03
  Russia's Veto Any plan for peace in Korea
- PRE-INAUGURAL FIREWORKS 1952 DEC 05
  wages prices steel costs ...for Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- CANNED 1952 DEC 08
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. "Wild Action" solutions of the Korean war
- YOU CROSS OUT THE "DAMNS" AND I'LL CROSS OUT THE "HELLS"! 1952 DEC 09
  House of Representatives Congress
- AND THE WALLS CAME A-TUMBLIN' DOWN! 1952 DEC 10
  Price controls & wage controls Coal
- OLD HATEFUL 1952 DEC 12
  Blasts at Eisenhower, Dwight D. Blasts at MacArthur, Douglas HST Truman, Harry S.
- WHITE CHRISTMAS 1952 DEC 16
  Political candidates, gubern for Governor Virginia
- WHERE DID EVERYONE GO? 1952 DEC 17
  Ridgway Goal $428 million for North Atlantic Treay Organization (NATO)
- THE OLD MASTER PAINTER 1952 DEC 24
  cheer
- THE WORLD'S GREATEST PEACE PLAN 1952 DEC 25
  Religion Luke 2 Fear not: for behold, I
- CHRISTMAS CASUALTY 1952 DEC 26
  Pinay
- READY AND WAITING 1953 JAN 05
  St. Lawrence Seaway Bricker amendment. Defense
- LOST IN A WHIRLPOOL 1953 JAN 09
  Generalities Eisenhower, Dwight D.'s State of the Union speech
- THEIR MAGIC CARPET 1953 JAN 12
  Your contribution to the March of Dimes Polio
- THE LITTLE RED SCHOOL HOUSE 1953 JAN 14
  Communist infiltration US schools
- THE WOLF IN SHEEP'S CLOTHING 1953 JAN 19
  Admin. wool plan old Brannan plan
- TWO EDGED SWORD 1953 JAN 20
  Integrity Responsibility Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- QUICKCHANGE ARTIST 1953 JAN 20
  Vote for Stanley Inauguration Address
- COME RIGHT IN AN' MAKE YOURSELF AT HOME! 1953 JAN 27
  North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) buildup Admin.
- OOPS! 1953 JAN 29
  HST Truman, Harry S. Atomic bomb A-bomb statement Explosive reaction
- LEAVING A WAKE 1953 FEB 04
  US seventh fleet United States Navy future action Formosa
- IF I HAD SOME HAM- I COULD HAVE SOME HAM AND EGGS- IF... 1953 FEB 05
  Whitehead
- BULLY! 1953 FEB 13
  Bomb goes off at Russian Legation in Tel-Aviv
- LEAKS IN THE D 1953 FEB 17
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. US Foreign aid Waste Duplication High living
- WHAT'S COOKIN'? 1953 FEB 21
  Congressional critics Secretary Benson
- WASHINGTON CHASM WHICH COMES FIRST 1953 FEB 24
  Taxes Cuts Balanced Budget
- HITCHING HER WAGON TO A STAR 1953 FEB 25
  statehood hopes Hawaii
- ROUND TRIP 1953 FEB 26
  Virginia Gubernatorial Ring Whitehead
- MIRAGE? 1953 FEB 27
  Political Heat Balanced budget in 1954 Political Parties Republican (GOP)
- RUB-A-DUB-DUB-THREE MEN IN A TUB... 1953 MAR 06
  Beria, Malenkov, Georgi M.Molotov, Vyacheslav M.
- FOLLOWING IN HIS FOOTSTEPS 1953 MAR 10
  Stalin, Joseph 's Power Malenkov, Georgi M.
- SOMEWHERE IN KOREA 1953 MAR 12
  Korea He died for lack of ammunition
- 195OLD BALDY3 MAR 27
- HOLD IT, I'VE THOUGHT OF ANOTHER ONE! 1953 MAR 31
  McCarthy, Joseph R. Wisconsin
- RUSSIAN EASTER EGG 1953 APR 01
  Russia our war weary world Communists (Reds) Peace Proposal
- WEIGHED DOWN 1953 APR 28
  Communists (Reds) Peace Dove Laos Invasion
- ANGELS WITH DIRTY FACES 1953 APR 30
  Ho Chi Minh Mao Tse-Tung Malenkov, Georgi M. Laos invasion
- ELUSIVE BUTTERFLY 1953 MAY 04
  Balanced Budget Political Parties Republican (GOP)
- RUSSIAN DOVE OF PEACE 1953 MAY 05
  Russia Peace Words not Deeds! Laos invasion
- FILL 'ER UP! 1953 MAY 07
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. $5,828,000,000 Foreign aid program Congress
- ACTION PACKED PICTURE OF THE 1953 GUBERNATORIAL RACE 1953 MAY 08
  Elections (blank)
- WISHING FOR THE MOON 1953 MAY 09
  Victorious '54 Elections Political parties Republican (GOP)
- WE CAN'T HEAR YOU, JOE! 1953 MAY 11
  Aggression in Asia Communists (Reds)s Peace, Peace
- THE KOREAN HILLS 1953 MAY 14
  Korea Truce Proposals Counter Proposals World
- THE HANDWRITING ON THE WALL 1953 MAY 15
  No Trade, No Foreign aid High Tariff boys
- SPRING PLANTING 1953 MAY 19
  '54 elections ground work
- SURPRISE! 1953 MAY 20
  Staggering costs of National security Eisenhower, Dwight D. Fed Budget
- THE ONE THAT GOT AWAY 1953 MAY 21
  John Q. Taxes Reduction
- CENTERPIECE 1953 MAY 25
  Worldwide problems Bermuda conference Britain United States
- SITTING IT OUT 1953 MAY 26
  Secret Truce Sessions in Korea
- STIRRING UP THE HORNET'S NEST 1953 MAY 29
  World Rx Taft's anti-United Nations speech
- THE SMALL TYPE 1953 JUN 01
  I'm all for Economy But constituents... Congress
- SPLITTING HEADACHE 1953 JUN 03
  Taft rift Congress Senate threat United Nations
- TOUGHER THAN EVEREST 1953 JUN 05
  Mt. Balanced Budget Defense costs
- STILL A LOT ON THE SHOPPING LIST! 1953 JUN 09
  Truce Armistice Formosa
- CLOUDING THE ISSUE 1953 JUN 10
  agreement South Korean Opposition truce
- NEW FOUND POLICY OF FREEDOM AND DEMOCRACY 1953 JUN 18
  Martial law East Berlin
- MILKING HER FOR ALL SHE'S WORTH 1953 JUN 29
  United Nations Rhee Concessions Korea
- IMPOSSIBLE TO PASS? 1953 JUL 02
  Rhee opposition United Nations
- UP IN SMOKE? 1953 JUL 03
  United Nations Rhee
- DUE PROCESS OF COMMUNIST LAW 1953 JUL 10
  Communists (Reds) East Germany
- HE'LL BE POPPING AGAIN 1953 JUL 11
  Communists (Reds) China Recognition New Truce Talks
- LIKE FATHER - LIKE SON 1953 JUL 22
  Old Reconstruction Finance Corporation (RFC) liquidated by Congress New Small Business Administration (SBA)
- BUT WHO WILL WATCH THE WATCHDOG? 1953 JUL 24
  Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) Unaccounted Spending
- NOT WHAT HE ORDERED 1953 JUL 25
  Platform Menu Elections Taxes Reduction Reduced Debt Budget
- POLITICAL SKYWRITING 1953 JUL 26
  Stevenson, Adlai E.
- ENTERING ANOTHER STATE 1953 JUL 29
  Welcome to the Cold War You are now lvg.
- NOT AS EASY AS IT LOOKS 1953 JUL 30
  All of the Elections campaign promises Political Parties Republican (GOP) Congress
- ROLLING OUR WAY 1953 AUG 03
  Red China Recognition problem United States
- INCOMPLETE - BUT A GOOD FOUNDATION 1953 AUG 05
  cuts in federal spending... budget
- NEW MAN IN THE DRIVER'S SEAT 1953 AUG 06
  Sen. Knowland Majority leader Political parties Republican (GOP)
- WHEAT GERM WARFARE 1953 AUG 08
  United StatesA Food East Germany Love Sam
- RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER, I'LL BE WAITING FOR YOU 1953 AUG 10
  Red China problem
- NEW STRONG MAN 1953 AUG 22
  Zahedi unsold oil idle oil wells Iran
- THE WORLD ON A STRING 1953 AUG 24
  hell Atomic bomb
- THE GREATEST SHOW ON EARTH 1953 AUG 25
  see the friendly bear East Germany
- THEY'RE DISCUSSING PEACE! 1953 AUG 26
  Peace United Nations foyer#1 John Q United Nations
- TROPHY ROOM 1953 AUG 27
  Used to split the United States from Allies United Nations Vishinsky
- FEELING THE HEAT 1953 AUG 30
  $9,000,000,000 federal debt Political parties Republican (GOP)
- SETTING HIS SIGHTS 1953 AUG 31
  Balanced budget New, brighter fed estimates
- SEPTEMBER MORN 1953 SEP 01
  The Cold War
- BOOK OF THE MONTH 1953 SEP 02
  How to keep cool
- I JUST CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT! 1953 SEP 03
  $100 Political parties Democrats (Dems) dinner menu regrets
- FINALLY OFF THE GROUND 1953 SEP 05
  Stanley Campaign Against Poll taxes Virginia
- CLOAK AND DAGGER 1953 SEP 12
  Partisan politics Robes of the Chief Justice Supreme Court
- I EXPECT TO REBUILD THE DEMOCRATIC PARTY ON ... SOUTH 1953 SEP 12
  Mitchell South Political parties Democrats (Dems)
- MOSQUITO PROBLEM 1953 SEP 15
  RFC Justice dept Int. Revenue 4% pentagon
- OUT ON A LIMB 1953 SEP 15
  West Trieste Problem Yugoslavia Italy
- MAGIC CARPET 1953 SEP 19
  5th Annual Tobacco festival Richmond, Virginia
- PASSING HIM BY 1953 SEP 21
  Red China UN
- FROM ONE WORLD TO ANOTHER 1953 SEP 22
  Mig Western freedom Eastern tyranny
- FROM HERE TO ETERNITY 1953 SEP 23
  many missing United States POW's behind Iron curtain
- TIME FOR A REAL TREAT! 1953 SEP 26
  Virginia Atlantic Rural Expositon
- THE SHADOW 1953 SEP 29
  New taxes to make up the Budget deficit Jan. 1 tax cut
- RECEPTION IS FINE 1953 SEP 30
  New United States Foreign aid for bases pact with Spain Franco, Francisco
- THE IN HUMAN RACE 1953 OCT 01
  World arms race armament build-up
- HAVE YOU MET THE NEW CHIEF JUSTICE? 1953 OCT 02
  Supreme Court judicial experience JQ
- FALL HARVEST 1953 OCT 07
  other hot spots indo-china crisis Korean flare-up
- ROCKING THE BOAT 1953 OCT 10
  Hydrogen bomb menace Political Parties Republican (GOP) Economy hopes
- RED SAILS IN THE SUNSET 1953 OCT 11
  Community chest needs your contribution
- HOW TIMES CHANGE! 1953 OCT 13
  1943 United States Bomb s German foe 1953 US builds Germany
- A WORM IN THE CORPS. 1953 OCT 15
  Security leaks United States Signal corps secrets
- THE NEW SERGEANT 1953 OCT 16
  Eisenhower, Dwight D.'s crackdown on balky government employees
- WHIRLWIND TOUR 1953 OCT 17
  Eisenhower, Dwight D.'s trip through the farmers belt Prices worries
- AUTUMN WINDS 1953 OCT 18
  Conference on Korea Conference on Trieste
- THE FROST IS ON THE PUMPKIN... 1953 OCT 19
  The cold war Our weary world
- A KNOTTY PROBLEM 1953 OCT 21
  Political parties Republican (GOP) Farmers policy
- NO REST FOR THE WEARY 1953 OCT 22
  Palestine nightmare Korea Trieste United Nations
- FRONT AND BACK 1953 OCT 23
  Miller Stanley But I am!
- A BITTER DOSE! 1953 OCT 28
  Communists (Reds) torture of United States Prisoners of War
- BOBBING FOR THE APPLE 1953 OCT 29
  World domination Communists (Reds)
- THE LATEST VOLUME 1953 OCT 31
  Japan atrocities Nazis Communists (Reds) in Korea
- WHICH WAY WILL THE WIND BLOW? 1953 NOV 02
  Virginia
- HIBERNATING 1953 NOV 06
  Home of the Russian Bear Don't want to negotiate
- BABY! IT'S COLD OUTSIDE! 1953 NOV 07
  Political Parties Democrats (Dems)ocratic drifts
- DONKEY SERENADE 1953 NOV 09
  From out of the past Truman, Harry Harry D. White, Harry D.
- I HAVE THE FEELING I'VE LOST SOMETHING! 1953 NOV 10
  Communists (Reds) repatriation efforts
- WHY NOT TRY FIXING THE ROOF? 1953 NOV 11
  Excessive spending Higher debt limit budget
- CALIFORNIA SUNSHINE 1953 NOV 12
  Gloomy predictions Elections Political Parties Republican (GOP) victory set backs
- THAT OUGHTA COVER IT UP! 1953 NOV 13
  It's all politics Communists (Reds) s in government
- OH SAY, CAN YOU SEE 1953 NOV 14
  Confusion Congress ional invest. of White, Harry D.
- AND I THOUGHT THEY WERE SHOOTING AT ME 1953 NOV 18
  Communists (Reds)s in govt Polit blasts
- WILTED LILY 1953 NOV 19
  Hoover, Herbert's scorching report of White, Harry D. case facts
- WORLD-WIDE SMOG 1953 NOV 23
  Confusion and mistrust
- YOO-HOO, SHERLOCK 1953 NOV 25
  Vanishing taxes Taft-Hartley Act Farmers policy
- COME YE THANKFUL PEOPLE, COME 1953 NOV 26
  Freedom of speech election worship
- A CLOUD LARGER THAN A MAN'S HAND 1953 NOV 27
  Solution Big 3 conference problem Bermuda
- HEY, YOU DON'T LOOK LIKE SANTA CLAUS 1953 NOV 28
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. bid to Big 4 conference Malenkov
- WILL THE CHLOROPHYLL DO THE JOB? 1953 NOV 30
  Absent voters' fraud 6 points Elections
- THE REAPER 1953 DEC 05
  Communists (Reds) atrocities
- MIND IF I LOOK OVER YOUR SHOULDER? 1953 DEC 07
  Proposed Big 4 conference meeting Bermuda
- FOR ALL THE WORLD TO SEE! 1953 DEC 10
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. proposal to pool atomic energy
- SIMPLE SIMON 1953 DEC 12
  United Nations Hope for Communists (Reds) cooperation in Korea
- GOSH! FOR ME? 1953 DEC 14
  Taxes reduction plan to John Q
- GETTING COLDER ALL THE TIME 1953 DEC 16
  Hopes for a quick Korean settlement
- FIRST OF ALL YOU'VE GOT TO GET A PASSPORT 1953 DEC 17
  Atomic secrets OK
- YEAR-ROUND SANTA 1953 DEC 18
  Christmas cards your mail man
- SOMETHING NEW FOR THIS YEAR'S TREE 1953 DEC 19
  Triple A ball Mayor Haddock (Mayor)
- TIME TO CATCH THE BULL BY THE HORNS 1953 DEC 21
  Virginia Highways problems Stanley
- SLIPPERY GOING! 1953 DEC 22
  Political parties Republican (GOP) program Political Parties Democrats (Dems) strength in Congress
- VISIONS OF SUGAR PLUMS DANCED IN HIS HEAD 1953 DEC 23
  Dear Uncle Sammy
- MY PEACE I GIVE UNTO YOU - JOHN 14:27 1953 DEC 25
  Peace Religion Our War-Weary World
- TWAS THE NIGHT AFTER CHRISTMAS AND ALL THROUGH THE HOUSE 1953 DEC 26
  Bills
- THE BIG PUSH 1953 DEC 30
  Legislative program 1954 Capitol Hill Congress Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- HOW ABOUT SOME OF THESE? 1953 DEC 31
  New Year's resolutions Understanding
- IT WILL POP UP A LITTLE HIGHER NOW 1954 JAN 02
  6.7% rate increase Virginia Electric & Power Company (VEPCO) Virginia State Corporation Commission SCC
- THE WORM IN THE APPLE 1954 JAN 04
  John Q. Boost in Social Security taxes
- CUM LAUDE? 1954 JAN 11
  New Atomic bombs tests More powerful weapons
- RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE 1954 JAN 12
  Labor farmers policy Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- PRIVATE CLUB 1954 JAN 16
  Virginia Senate privileges Virginia Political Parties Republican (GOP)
- IF THEY PUT IN THIS TOLL ROAD WHAT'LL WE DO FOR INCOME 1954 JAN 21
  plans Highways Virginia
- EN GARDE! 1954 JAN 22
  federal spending plans to cut down the budget Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- THE FOAM ON THE BEER 1954 FEB 02
  propaganda Big 4 conference in Berlin
- PUSHING IT ALONG 1954 FEB 05
  Byrd, Harry F., Sr. machine Gas Taxes increase
- HOW'RE YOU FIXED FOR BLADES? 1954 FEB 06
  Virginia Elections Outdated poll taxes fee
- LOOKING OVER HIS SHOULDER 1954 FEB 10
  Alcholic Beverage Control statutes budget gas taxes agenda
- WATCH YOUR STEP 1954 FEB 11
  Big 4 coference deadlock in Berlin Indo-china War West
- COME RIGHT IN, WE'VE BEEN WAITING FOR YOU 1954 FEB 13
  Virginia Senate taxes refund
- MIND IF I MAKE A SUGGESTION? 1954 FEB 15
  Highways Petersburg Pike Virginia tie-up Toll Road
- DEAD END STREET 1954 FEB 17
  Big 4 conference Berlin The West
- PUNCHY! 1954 FEB 18
  income taxes gas excise license property John Q
- BLOT ON THE PAPER 1954 FEB 19
  The White House Firing of Clarence Manion, Clarence
- CONGRESSIONAL DECORATION 1954 FEB 23
  The United State Army McCarthy, Joseph
- SCRAPPED 1954 FEB 25
  Haag-Waddell Commission Commissions Gray Commission Crocket Commission Marr Commission
- THE BIG GUNS 1954 FEB 26
  McCarthy, Joseph blasts Stevens ' capitulation
- I THINK I PRETTY WELL SENSE THE WILL OF THE ASSEMBLY 1954 FEB 27
  Virginia General Assembly Stanley
- FAMILY PLOT 1954 MAR 01
  Taxes Poll tax repeals killed... Campbell amendment s
- THE ADDICT 1954 MAR 03
  Fanatacism Puerto Rican nationalists
- MARCH WIND 1954 MAR 06
  McCarthy, Joseph feud Political Parties Republican (GOP)
- SOMETHING'S SHRUNK! 1954 MAR 09
  High level of politics A. Stevenson, Adlai E.
- THERE'S PLENTY OF FREE AIR TIME! 1954 MAR 10
  Stevenson, Adlai E. McCarthy, Joseph spokesmen
- MESSAGE FOR TODAY 1954 MAR 11
  How do you... Red Cross... great organization
- DIGGING HIM UP AGAIN 1954 MAR 17
  The Political Parties Republican (GOP) is the party of the rich
- THE CHALLENGE 1954 MAR 19
  World wide Religion atomic bombs war Christian understanding
- STRINGS ATTACHED 1954 MAR 20
  Elections year politics Political Parties Democrats (Dems) taxes cut plans
- REMEMBER? 1954 MAR 22
  The only thing we have to fear... We're heading for...
- SPRING TIME 1954 MAR 24
  Hydrogen bomb World Atomic bombs Destruction
- ROLL OUT THE BARREL... 1954 MAR 29
  Taxes cuts and bigger deficits budget
- THE COURSE OF THE NILE 1954 MAR 31
  Turmoil Egypt
- THE OFFICE CREW FIGHTING THE NEW PARKING RULE 1954 APR 03
  evade 500'
- SAND TRAP 1954 APR 05
  Elections year politics Political Parties Republican (GOP) Legislative program
- NOT BY THE HAIR OF MY CHINNY-CHIN-CHIN 1954 APR 06
  North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Russia
- NOW I HAVE HERE... 1954 APR 12
  Dulles, John F. United Action Allies France Britain
- EGG HUNT 1954 APR 13
  Political Parties Republican (GOP) seats in Congress votes
- TERMITES 1954 APR 14
  Federal Housing Administration Frauds
- DAZED 1954 APR 17
  The Oppenheimer Case John Q
- COLD FRONT 1954 APR 21
  public opposition to sending United States Army troops - Indo-china
- MISPLACED SPOTLIGHT 1954 APR 23
  McCarthy, Joseph 's charges - counter charges Communists (Reds) s
- TESTING -1 -2 -3 -TESTING 1954 APR 24
  Admin program public opinion on war
- ONLOOKERS 1954 APR 26
  Geneva conference Ethiopian crisis disarmament ...
- SNAILSPACE 1954 APR 27
  Eisenhower, Dwight D. program Congress ional action
- THE JOKER IN THE DECK 1954 APR 28
  Russian cards Recognition of Red China
- HELP! 1954 APR 29
  Army - McCarthy, Joseph hearings John Q
- HEY! 1954 APR 30
  Another Korean pitfall Indo-china War